# **Andrew Paschall**

602.615.0610 | paschallandrew@gmail.com | Phoenix, AZ

**LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/andrew-paschall Website: andrewpaschall.com

## QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

I am a hands-on Salesforce Architect with 14 years of experience building business-critical solutions in various domains and industries. I specialize in technical Salesforce roles that utilize my strong presentation and facilitation skills, obtaining stakeholder acceptance by understanding and delivering the right strategic vision, and driving the difficult conversations necessary to execute business strategies.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

• Salesforce, JavaScript, JSON, APIs, APEX, LWC, SLDS, Node.js, jQuery, SQL, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, Git, Mulesoft, PHP, Java, Blockchain, Jira, Agile

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Salesforce Development Manager | Allstate Identity Protection | Scottsdale, AZ

Feb 2021 – Present

- Build, lead and mentor a high-performing team of 5 Salesforce developers and administrators
- Deliver live product demonstrations, technical Q&A, and roadmap presentation to C-suite stakeholders
- Develop a program vision while advising and articulating program/project strategies on Salesforce platform
- Responsible for hands-on development of key features as well as security and code quality of the team
- Build relationships with internal/external customers, manage expectations and negotiate solutions to complex problems with both the customer and third-party partners

# Salesforce Solutions Architect | Allstate Identity Protection | Scottsdale, AZ

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- Technical lead for team implementing Sales/Service/Community Clouds, Lightning Experience and SSO
- Designed and developed functional solution architecture, proof-of-concepts, demos, and best practices
- Designed and implemented call center applications in Salesforce using Lightning Web Components, Custom Object design, Apex, JavaScript, SLDS, REST APIs, MuleSoft, and Genesys
- Developed NetSuite ERP integration using Salesforce LWC, Apex, and Mulesoft to sync client payment data
- Implemented a Salesforce-native Contract Lifecycle Management solution (Conga CLM) to house all contract processes, templates, signing, maintenance and data governance on the Salesforce platform

## Salesforce Solutions Architect | Shellback Semiconductor | Phoenix, AZ

Feb 2018 - Mar 2019

- Led and completed company-wide implementation of Salesforce Lightning over 6 months. Tools included
  Custom Object Design, LWC, Visualforce, Flows, Process Builder, SOQL queries, Data Loader and Apex triggers
- Built rich, highly performant applications using Lightning, Apex, and LWC JavaScript frameworks
- Lead Sales and Service process engineer for OEM Group's worldwide ERP migration
- Reduced quarterly forecast error by more than 45% via data analysis and custom Salesforce reporting

## User Experience Director (UX) | Multivista | Phoenix, AZ

May 2013 - Dec 2017

- Responsible for the design, planning, programming and maintenance of the company's public website, mobile app, Salesforce CRM, and desk.com support portals
- Responsible for Salesforce integrations with Hubspot, Marketo and the company's proprietary platforms
- Designed and implemented Marketing processes in Salesforce to automate communications between Sales and Marketing and assign campaign influence to opportunities for real-time ROI reporting
- Led all UX/UI design for the company's mobile/tablet application for iOS, Android and mobile web

# Lead Web Developer | Multivista | Phoenix, AZ

May 2011 - Apr 2013

- Redesigned, coded, and re-launched the Multivista website HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript standards; improved the company's visibility within the market and facilitated a 23% total sales increase from web leads
- Implemented open-source mapping tools to replace the company's existing proprietary solution, saving more than \$40,000 per year
- Designed interactive help systems for new customers, driving a 30% decrease in new account support calls

### Web Developer (Freelance Consulting) | Cleartorch, Inc. | Phoenix, AZ

Feb 2006 - Apr 2011

- Provided full-stack web development and marketing automation solutions to small to medium size companies across the U.S., primarily servicing the Financial Services, Healthcare and Higher Education industries.
- Technologies included HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, WordPress and Drupal.

As a Freelance Web Developer my day-to-day activities with clients include:

- Conduct UX research using research tools and create project report
- Create sketch, wireframe, prototype and visual mockups
- Design and develop UI Designs with Sketch and/or Photoshop for clients
- Responsible for the accuracy and editorial integrity of text on site
- Set up A/B testing using Visual Website Optimizer and reviewed and analyzed results with team
- Advocate web interaction design best practices, with a focus on consistency and usability
- Oversee content on websites and monitor traffic to ensure functionality
- Set up and monitored Google Adwords advertising campaigns and conducted keyword research
- Use SEO tools and applications to assist with Google search engine rankings
- Monitored user experience and interaction with webpages using tracking tools
- Work with backend engineers to see projects through, from conception to completion
- Design functionality of apps and web applications

#### **EDUCATION**

Certified Salesforce Platform Developer I Certified Salesforce Platform App Builder Certified Salesforce Administrator **B.A. English,** *Arizona State University*